字幕出自 Netflix，提前 16 秒对应 BD Subtitles from Netflix, 16 seconds ahead for BD Netflixの字幕、BDは16秒先読 み
字幕出自 Netflix，提前 16 秒对应 BD Subtitles from Netflix, 16 seconds ahead for BD Netflixの字幕、BDは16秒先読 み
Forgive me!
对不起！
I missed your heart.
我没击中你的致命点
I'll end it quickly!
我会帮你快速了结的！
Askeladd.
阿谢拉特…
I wanted to be your friend.
我希望我们是朋友…
Yes, Bjorn.
是的 表伦
You…
你…
were my only…
是我唯一一个
true friend.
朋友
Send me off.
送我上路吧…
Now then.
那么
Sorry to keep you waiting, kid.
抱歉让你等我 小子
Come.
来吧
I'll play with you.
我来陪你玩
EPISODE 22: LONE WOLF
（第22集：孤狼）
Damn it.
该死的
He's different from usual.
他和往常不大一样
So, who do you think will win, Prince?
王子 你觉得谁会赢？
Want to bet on it?
想不想打个赌？
It doesn't matter who wins.
谁赢都无所谓
I'll stop it before either dies.
有人死之前我会让他们停下来
How could you say a thing like that?
别这么说
A duel between two master swordsmen is not something you see every day.
两个剑术高手之间的决斗 可不是你每天都看得到的东西
In that case,
这样的话
who do you believe is stronger between them?
你觉得他们俩之间谁更强呢？
Me?
我？
Let's see…
我想想…
Askeladd, I guess.
我猜 是阿谢拉特吧
I'd bet one pound of silver on him.
我赌一磅白银他会赢
I'm not betting.
我不赌
Why do you think so?
你为什么这么想？
That's the impression I get from his aura?
就是感觉吧 可能是他散发的气质？
Thorfinn managed to beat you.
托尔芬可是赢了你
Is Askeladd even stronger?
难道阿谢拉特还要更强？
Little prince, are you mocking me?
你个臭小子王子 你是在嘲笑我吗？
Between the three of us, there's no way I'd be the weakest. Got it?
我们这三个人里 我不可能是最弱一个 懂吗？
It's not just a matter of who's stronger or weaker.
不是说谁更强谁更弱这么简单
It's interesting because there is no measuring who will win or lose.
这很有意思 因为没法衡量 谁会赢或者谁会输
I'm not interested.
我不感兴趣
You really are a girl.
那看来你还真是个女人
What's wrong, Thorfinn?
托尔芬 怎么了？
Attack me.
冲我来啊
Let's finish this before more snow falls.
在雪下大之前 我们把这件事情解决掉
Guess you leave me no choice.
你让我别无选择
There. This will should simply things.
这样 这样你攻击我更容易了吧？
Come on, brat.
来啊 小子
See?
看到没？
You still don't get it do you? Why it always ends like this?
你还是不明白为什么会是这种结果？
I stand corrected. This isn't a duel at all.
我说错了 这根本不是决斗
Askeladd knows all Thorfinn's tendencies. He sees right through him.
阿谢拉特知道托尔芬的习性 他一眼就能把他看穿
I wonder what the reason is.
他们为什么要决斗？
I don't know.
我不知道 我没问
Good grief.
老天啊
This kid never learns.
这孩子就是学不会
Did you get cocky after beating Thorkell?
你打败了托鲁克尔所以就自满了吗？
I'm getting sick and tired of this.
我受够这个了
Stop! That's enough!
停下！够了！
You really thought you could beat me with one arm?
你真觉得用一只手臂就能打败我吗？
Good God.
天哪
I sure am having a wonderful day.
我今天过得真不错
Stop!
停下！
That's enough!
早就够了
He's unconscious.
他已经失去意识了
You've won.
你赢了
Are you serious?
他真的让他们停下了？
Thorfinn.
托尔芬
Hey, Thorfinn.
嘿 托尔芬
You understand?
你明白的 对吧？
The duel is over.
决斗结束了
You lost.
你输了
Stop. It's over.
停下 结束了
You bastard!
你个混蛋！
You lost consciousness.
你都失去意识了
He could have ended you.
他都准备好要杀你了
Duel again once your arm heals.
等你右手臂好了再决斗
That won't change anything.
好了也一样
The arm's not the problem.
他输不是因为受伤
That fool lost because he's an idiot.
这个笨蛋输是因为他是个笨蛋
Normally, you think when you're fighting.
通常来说 你打斗的时候会思考
But you screw it all up when you lose your temper.
但你让怒气冲昏了头脑 就都搞砸了
I can tell by your gaze that you're aiming for my jugular.
从你的眼神里我就能看出来 你对准了我的颈静脉
You rage, shriek like a madman,
你很快就开始愤怒 大声尖叫
and wave your daggers like an amateur.
像个战场上的白痴一样到处挥剑
How tiresome it is. Not one of you has a shred of beauty.
你们真是一点美感都没有
It's just as Bjorn said.
就像表伦说的
I hate warriors.
我讨厌战士
Especially you Norse warriors, you Vikings.
尤其是挪威战士 维京人
The first person I killed was a Norse warrior.
我杀的第一个人也是个挪威战士
And he too was devoid of beauty.
那个男人一点没有美感
That man was my father.
那是我父亲
Boy.
小子
For future reference, I will tell you…
我给你提个醒
how to properly kill
告诉你怎么杀那个让你厌恶的人
-Oh, this is hot. -I'm getting too old for this.
好了 可真热…
Watch out.
小心你后面
My mother was a slave.
我母亲是个奴隶
My mother was sick, so she couldn't work.
我母亲病了 所以不能干活
As far back as I can remember, I worked with a blacksmith in stables.
从我记事起 我就在马厩里 和铁匠一起干活
I was always covered in ash, soot, or horse shit,
我身上总是布满了灰尘 煤烟或者马屎
turning me black and white.
让我要么黑要么白
So they called me "Askeladd."
所以 我被叫做“阿谢拉特”
It means "covered in ash."
意思是“被灰尘覆盖”
Lord Olaf has returned home!
奥拉夫大人回家啦！
He was victorious once again!
他又一次胜利了！
My father came from a powerful Jutland family.
我父亲来自日德兰半岛 一个有权势的家族
-Lord Olaf! -Welcome home, Lord Olaf!
-奥拉夫大人！ -奥拉夫大人 欢迎回家！
He liked booze, women, and killing.
他喜欢酒 女人 还有杀戮…
He was as typical a Viking as they come.
他是个你到处可见的典型维京人
He had many other children like me born to other women.
他有好几个像我这样 和妻子之外的女人生的孩子
But he only gave names to his older children born to his wife.
但他只给他妻子生的几个
He probably didn't know the faces of his other children.
他可能根本不记得其他几个孩子的脸
When my mother was young,
我母亲年轻的时候
she seemed to be my father's favorite slave.
似乎是我父亲最喜欢的奴隶
But when she fell ill, he treated her no better than a dog.
但她病了 他对待她就像对待一条狗
I understood then that life was full of strife.
我很清楚生活是很艰难的
But somehow, my mother still maintained hope.
但对我母亲来说 好像不一样
My mother often spoke of our ancestor, the hero Artorius.
我母亲总是说到我们的祖先 英雄阿托利斯
She told the same story countless times.
她无数次对我说了相同的故事
It was the legend of the general who protected my mother's homeland
那是将军的传说
She believed in the legend of that hero's return.
她相信英雄回归的传说
That someday he would return to free her from sickness and slavery.
总有一天 他会回来 从疾病和奴役中把她救出来
She repeated it so many times that I began to believe it myself.
她说了太多次 我也开始相信了
She said that beyond the far west,
在遥远的西边
there was a perfect place, that no ordinary person could reach.
那是个完美的地方 普通人到不了
The hero Artorius lived in that paradise.
他们说 在那里 英雄阿托利斯住在天堂里
It was a promised land
那个宁静又丰裕的乐土中 没人会老也没人会死
Supposedly, that hero is still there tending to his battle wounds.
那个英雄现在应该在那里 治他战斗中受的伤
Someday, he will return to lead the army that will vanquish the barbarians.
总有一天 他会带领着大军
And he will rule over the world.
然后统治世界
My mother's people continue to wait for that day.
我母亲的族人一直在等待那一天到来
They have been waiting for 500 years.
他们等了又等 等了五百年
But their hero
英雄…却还是没出现
But think about it.
但想想看
If my ancestor was truly living in a such a wonderful place,
如果我的祖先 真的生活在这么美好的地方
he would never give that up to come back to this world.
他永远也不会放弃那个地方 回到这个世界来
And then,
后来
when I was 11 years old, my mother's spirit finally broke.
我十一岁的时候 我母亲终于疯了
Mother!
母亲！
Of all people,
巧的是
my father happened to be passing by, and she decided he was the hero Artorius.
那天被她当成英雄阿托利斯的
I realized at that moment…
那一刻我明白了
that if Artorius did not appear then to save my mother,
如果阿托利斯这个时候 都不出来救我的母亲
he would never appear for all eternity.
那么这样一个人永远也不会出现
Do you understand, boys?
小子们 你们明白了吗？
Somebody must do it.
总得有人来干
It won't be a hero or a god,
不会是英雄或者上帝
but somebody else.
而是别的人
It was a mysterious thing.
这真是神秘的事情
It was my first time using a sword, but holding it felt natural.
那是我第一次用剑 但拿在手里就觉得很自然
I instinctively knew how to wield it.
我知道怎么挥剑
It seemed proof that I had that bastard's blood flowing in me.
我相信这证明了那个混蛋的血液 确实流淌在我身体里
It was a sad spectacle.
真是可悲
It pains me to this day.
让我想哭
You.
你…
Are you that woman's child?
你是那个女人的孩子吗？
Are you my child?
你是我的孩子吗？
Yes.
对
You have promise.
你很有潜力
You will live in my home.
今天起 你住到我家里去
I certainly didn't think that an 11-year-old could kill him.
我当然知道 一个十一岁的孩子杀不了他
But the first step was to get his attention.
但我吸引我父亲注意的第一步
This I had accomplished.
很成功
At his manor, I refined my etiquette.
在他的庄园里 我学会了礼仪
I learned the arts of swordsmanship and equestrianism.
也没有忽略武艺或者马术的训练
I also got along well with my older half-brothers.
我和我同父异母的兄弟们 也相处得很好
-Well done, Askeladd. -Not bad at all.
-干得不错 阿谢拉特 -非常不错
I was always careful to show respect to my father.
我一直很小心地 表现出对我父亲的尊重
I was his faithful son.
我是他忠实的儿子
I never forgot that he saved me from slavehood.
并且没有忘记是他 把我从奴隶生活中救出来的
Before long, his servants and men completely accepted me as his son.
很快 他的仆人们还有身边的人 完全接受了我是他儿子的身份
I lived like that for two years.
就这样 我秘密行动了两年
I was waiting for two things,
我要寻找两样东西：
a moment when he'd be careless and the rights to his inheritance.
我父亲的大意 还有继承的权利
I wish you boys could see the look on his face.
真想让你们看看
My father's face asking, "Why?"
我父亲问“为什么？”时候的表情
I used my older brother's sword.
我用的是我哥哥的剑
I stole it from a son who didn't get along with him.
我从和我父亲关系不好的儿子那里 偷来了剑
The other brothers believed he was the murder.
其他兄弟们认为他是凶手
So they hung him from the bough of tree,
他们把他吊起来私刑绞死
the simple, naive fools.
真是一群白痴
They were all stupid and obscene,
他们统统都既愚蠢又下流
a horde of crude barbarians who knew nothing but greed.
就是一群除了贪婪 什么都不知道的垃圾
Ugly bastards like that sprung out from every place I looked
散播在各地的这种丑陋私生子们
and made their presence known.
从四面八方冒出来
I could have never killed them all.
无论我杀多少 都杀不光
It doesn't matter if it's Artorius, Ragnarok, or the Last Judgment.
不管是阿托利斯 拉格纳 还是最后的审判
But if something is coming, I wish it would hurry up.
如果真的有事情发生 那么我希望快一点发生
Well, when that day comes, I probably won't survive it.
不过我可能等不到那一天真的到来
I've rambled for too long.
我胡扯了太久了
To put it simply, Thorfinn…
托尔芬 简单来说
since you've failed to defeat me over these past ten years
已经十多年了 你是还没有击败我
you are an idiot.
你就是个笨蛋
No matter what happens, I will kill you!
不管发生什么 我都会杀了你！
I swear I will kill you!
我一定会杀了你！
Good grief.
老天啊
You still say that after what I just told you?
我跟你说了那么多 你还是这么说？
You're like a dog chasing his own tail.
你就像条到处追着食物走的狗
I respect your determination and work ethic.
我尊重你的职业道德
All I've had to do is agree to these ridiculous duels,
我只要配合你进行这些可笑的决斗
and you've eagerly gone off to challenge even Thorkell.
你就那么迫切地去挑战 哪怕是托鲁克尔这样的人
What a useful brat you've been all these years.
真是个好用的小子啊
Goodness.
天哪
I should be grateful to Thors too.
我也应该感谢托尔兹
Wait.
等等…
Wait!
等等！
Enough already.
够了
Shut up!
闭嘴！
Keep your mouth shut!
闭上你的嘴！
Heal your wounds.
先把你的伤养好
Wait.
等等…
Just stop!
停下！
Pathetic.
真可悲
Good grief.
老天啊
You're stiff as a board now, Bjorn.
表伦 你现在硬得像块木板
Wait.
为什么是我呢？
You're the descendant of a hero, Askeladd.
因为你是英雄的后代 阿谢拉特
And you're wise.
而且你很聪明
Don't you think that if you were king, you could change the world?
你难道不认为如果你是国王的话 你能改变世界？
That's hilarious.
你开玩笑吧
Didn't you hear my story?
你没听我的故事吗？
You are more suited for the throne.
你更适合当国王
More than me or King Sweyn.
比我和斯韦恩国王更适合
I can tell by your face.
从你的脸上我就能看出来
I am but a Viking.
我不过是个维京人